Union Memorabilia Collection 6043 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Union Memorabilia Collection
1953-1963
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel Center
6043 MB
3.72 cubic feet
3.6 linear ft.
Memorabilia.
11035746
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 15, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 29, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Clothing trade; Glassworkers; Labor unions; Heckinger, Charles; Jackson, Jesse, 1941-; Nixon, Richard M.(Richard Milhous), 1913- 1994; Reagan, Ronald; AFL-CIO --Archives; AFL-CIO. Building and Construction Trades Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Connecticut State Labor Council--Archives; AFSCME --Archives; Alliance for Labor Action --Archives; Amalgamated Association of Street and Electric Railway Employees of America --Archives; Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America --Archives; Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America; Amalgamated Transit Union --Archives; American Federation of Musicians --Archives; American Federation of Teachers --Archives; American Federation of Technical Engineers --Archives; American Flint Glass Workers' Union --Archives; American Newspaper Guild --Archives; Ancient Order of United Workmen --Archives; Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers (U.S.) --Archives; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen --Archives; Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen --Archives; Building Service Employee's International Union --Archives; Canadian Labour Congress --Archives; Cannery & Agricultural Workers Industrial Union --Archives; CAW-Canada --Archives; Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America --Archives; Continental Airlines --Archives; Culinary Workers Alliance, United Public Workers of America --Archives; Engineers Political Education Committee --Archives; General Motors Corporation --Archives; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America --Archives; Insurance Agents' International Union --Archives; International Association Bridge Structural, and Ornamental Iron Workers --Archives; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers --Archives; International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers and Helpers --Archives; International Brotherhood of Operative Potters --Archives; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America --Archives; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Office and Professional Employees International Union --Archives; International Chemical Workers Union --Archives; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union --Archives; International Masonry Institute --Archives; International Typographical Union --Archives; International Typographical Union. Local 232 (Binghamton, N.Y.)--Archives; International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers, Steel Workers Organizing Committee --Archives; International Union, Allied Industrial Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, UAW-CIO --Archives; Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union --Archives; Journeymen Barbers, Hairdressers, Cosmetologists, and Proprietors' International Union of America --Archives; Massachusetts State Labor Council --Archives; Metal Spinners Union --Archives; National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians --Archives; National Association of Letter Carriers (U.S.) --Archives; National Association of Retired Civil Employees --Archives; National Council of Grain Processors --Archives; National Union of the United Brewery Workers --Archives; New York (State). Department of Labor--Archives; New York State Teachers Association --Archives; Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union; Operative Plasterers' and Cement Masons' International Association of the United States and Canada --Archives; Order of Railroad Telegraphers (U.S.) --Archives; Playthings, Jewelry and Novelty Workers International Union --Archives; Production Engineers Society --Archives; Sears, Roebuck and Company --Archives; Switchmen's Union of North America --Archives; Telecommunications International Union --Archives; Textile Workers Organizing Committee --Archives; ULLICO Inc. --Archives; United Automobile Workers of America (CIO) --Archives; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America --Archives; United Farm Workers --Archives; United Federation of Postal Clerks --Archives; United Furniture Workers of America --Archives; United Glass and Ceramic Workers of North America --Archives; United Packinghouse Workers of America --Archives; United States. Department of Labor--Archives; United Steelworkers of America; Utica Central Trades & Labor Council --Archives; Washington (State). Industrial Welfare Commission--Archives; West Virginia Labor Federation --Archives; Workers Alliance of America --Archives; Workers' Defense League --Archives
11035746
- A.F.L. - Badges, Pins, funny money, Officer cards, 1927-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- AFL Building Trades Dept. - Pins (Newport News Building & Constructions Trades Council; Union card, 1915-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A.F.L.-C.I.O. - Badges, Pins, Buttons, Comb, Post-Card, Bumper sticker, metal plate, 1955-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO New Jersey - Badge (Box 1, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO, Rochester & Vicinity Labor Council - Magnets, Pins, Bumper Stickers, Broadsides (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America - 2 decks of cards (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Amalgamated Sheet Metal Workers - Union label stamps (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Amalgamated Transit Union - Buttons, Pins, Pens, Key chains, Pocket protector (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Automobile Workers - Badges, Buttons, Pins, stickers, Bumper Stickers, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bakery Confectionary & Tobacco Workers - Buttons, stickers (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Journeymen Barbers International Union - Union Shop! (sign) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Scope and Contents
  information backing to sign, is very brittle
- Beauty Shop Union - Badge, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bricklayers, Masons and Plasterers' International Union of America - Stickers, Due book, Bumper sticker, Broadsides (Box 1, Folder 13)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America - Ruler, Stickers, Badges, Buttons (Box 1, Folder 14)
- CIO - Badges, Stamps (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CIO, Michigan Council - Lapel Pin (Box 1, Folder 16)
- United Cement, Lime & Gypsum - Button and Due book, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Central Labor Union - Badge (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cigar Makers International Union - Souvenir pencils (4) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  removed from collection 5278
- Amalgamated Clothing & Textile Workers Union - Clinton/Gore button (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Communications Workers of America - Broadsides and Bumper Sticker (Box 1, Folder 21)
- United Dairy Workers of America - Buttons (Box 1, Folder 22)
- United Electrical Radio and Machine Workers - Buttons and Pin (Box 1, Folder 23)
- International Association Fire Fighters - Bumper Sticker, Stickers, Certificate (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union - Buttons, Paper hats, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Glazers, Architectural Metal, Glass Workers - Stickers (Box 1, Folder 26)
- AFGE - Buttons for Clinton (Box 1, Folder 27)
- American Federation of Grain Millers' International Union of A.F. of L. - empty match book (Box 1, Folder 28)
- International Hod Carriers Building and Common Laborers' Union of America - Buttons, Membership book, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- ILGWU - Buttons - Clinton/Gore (Box 1, Folder 30)
- International Railway Freight Handlers - Button, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- International Union of Operating Engineers - Stickers, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- IVES - Button (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Knights of Labor broadside (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Laborers' International Union of North America - Buttons, Membership book, 1942-1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- International Longshoremen's Association - Buttons, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- International Association of Machinists - Badges, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employes - Stickers (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Mechanics Educational Society of America - Buttons (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Milk Drivers Protective, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- United Mine Workers of America - Button, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- National Association of Motor Bus Operators - Badges, 1926-1939 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- National Education Association - Mondale/Ferraro Bumper Sticker, Buttons, 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- National Fraternal Congress of America - Badge, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Minnesota State Federation of Labor - Badge, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Newspaper Guild - Buttons, Stickers (Box 1, Folder 46)
- New York State AFL-CIO - Badges, Stickers, Broadsides, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- United Paperworkers International Union - Bumper Stickers (Box 1, Folder 48)
- New York State Association of Master Plumbers - Badges, 1921-1931 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- American Postal Workers Union - Pen, Key Chain, Women's History Month with pride ribbon (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill workers - Key chain, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employes - Buttons, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- American Association of Santa Fe Employes - Button (Box 1, Folder 53)
- National Rural Letter Carriers Association - Badge, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Western States Service Station Employees Union - Sticker (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Sheet Metal Workers International Association - Sticker (Box 1, Folder 56)
- AFSCME - Buttons, souvenir pencil (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Amalgamated Association of Street and Electric Railway Employes of America, Division 268 - Button, 1943-1959 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America - Buttons, stickers, 1941-1959 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Telecommunications International Union - Pens, Comb, Buttons (Box 1, Folder 60)
- International Typographical Union - Badge, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- ILGWU - Badges, 1900-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO - Badges, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO - Badges, Buttons, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- U.B. of c. & J. of A. - Badges, AFL-CIO - Badges, Canadian labour Congress - Badge, 1958-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- United Farm Workers - Buttons (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Switchmen's Union of North America - Buttons, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Brotherhood of Linemen, Firemen & Engineers - Badges; United Packinghouse Workers of America - Ribbon, 1900- 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Misc. Union- Buttons, Badges, Tie clips, Pins, 1931-1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  AFL-CIO; United Teachers of New York State; United Farm Workers; IAM; AFT; B. of R.T.
- AFL-CIO, CIO, American Federation of Labor, ALA - Badges, 1953-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- International Association of Machinists - Badge (Box 2, Folder 10)
- AFL-CIO - Badges, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers - Badges, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- AFL-CIO - Badges, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- AFL-CIO, Convention Badges, 1955-1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- AFL-CIO Convention Badges, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Misc. Union Badges, Buttons, Pins, etc., 1955-1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Misc. Union Buttons, Ribbons, etc., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Misc. Union - Badges, Buttons, and Letter Opener (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Misc. Union Buttons (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Brotherhood of Railway, Airline Buttons, 1916-1955 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- UAW, Transport Workers, Packinghouse Wkrs, Radio Buttons, 1937-1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Furniture, Mine, Steel Workers buttons, 1937-1951 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Shipyard Workers, Carpenters, Hod Carriers - Badges, Buttons, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- National Council of Grain Processors - Buttons, 1934-1941 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Misc. Labor Union Buttons, 1938-1944 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- International Longshoremen's Association - Buttons, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- CIO - Push pins & Badges, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Misc. Labor Union - Buttons - Badge, 1943-1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Misc. Labor Union Push Pins, Badges, Cuff Link, etc (Box 2, Folder 29)
- United Brewery Workers, National Union Sticker (Box 2, Folder 30)
- United Farm Workers - Buttons (Box 2, Folder 31)
- United Steelworkers - membership card, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Utica Control Trades & Labor Council - Advertisements, Membership papers, 1886-1923 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Washington (State) Apprentices - License to Apprentice, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Workers Defense League - button (Box 2, Folder 35)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters - Buttons, Pins, Pendants, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Misc. - AFL-CIO affiliated unions - Pendant and Pins, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Misc. AFL-CIO affiliated - Badges, Pins, Pendants, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters Buttons, 1920-1952 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- AFL-CIO, Int'l. Brotherhood of Teamsters, etc. - Pendants, buttons (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Misc. Union Buttons (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Misc. Union Buttons (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Brotherhood of Railway, Airline Buttons (Box 2, Folder 43)
- National Council of Grain Processors - Buttons (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Misc. Union Memorabilia - Buttons, tie tack, coins, pins, bumper stickers, broadsides, advertisements, etc. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- United Paperworkers - Buttons (Box 3, Folder 2)
- EPEC - push pins, key chain, 1976-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO - Badges, 1957-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO - Badges, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- AFL-CIO - Badges, 1961-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- International Union of Operating Engineers - key chains, badges, etc. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Political Collectibles - buttons, etc., 1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Misc. -- United Farm Workers; New York State Federation of Labor; Friends of the Dept. of Labor; - patch, badges, key chain, money clip, small knife, buttons (Box 3, Folder 9)
- NYSUT buttons, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Pennsylvania AFL-CIO - badges, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Eastern Academy of Management - t-shirt, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Teamsters corduroy cap; 45th Consecutive Constitutional Convention, UMWA, Mallet; Shears; Lessons in Cutting (book); CAW t-shirt (Box 3, Folder 13)
  all items are in box loose
- Misc. Union Buttons (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Misc. Union Buttons (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Misc. Union Buttons (Box 4, Folder 3)
- United Steelworkers of America - Union Duty Card, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- The Creed of the Butcher Workman; AFSCME sign (Box 5, Folder 1)